[
	{
		"question": "How would you inspect for rot (decay)?",
		"options": [
			"Inspect for a dark discolouration of the wood surface or gray stains along the grain.",
			"Look for signs of termites.",
			"Apply a coating of oil and look for where it turns blue"
		],
		"answer": "Inspect for a dark discolouration of the wood surface or gray stains along the grain."
	},
	{
		"question": "What three forms of wood are used in aircraft?",
		"options": [
			"Solid, Laminated, and Plywood",
			"Square, Sheet, and Paper",
			"Particle board, Orientated Strand Board, and Composite"
		],
		"answer": "Solid, Laminated, and Plywood"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is a laminated wood assembly?",
		"options": [
			"Two or more layers glued together with the grain of all layers approximately parallel",
			"Two or more layers glues together with the grain of all layers approximately perpendicular",
			"Running the wood through a lamination machine"
		],
		"answer": "Two or more layers glued together with the grain of all layers approximately parallel"
	},
	{
		"question": "What specie of wood is used as a standard for strength?",
		"options": ["Spruce", "Pine", "Oak"],
		"answer": "Spruce"
	},
	{
		"question": "Are hard knots acceptable?",
		"options": [
			"Yes, within the specified limits",
			"Yes, always",
			"No, never"
		],
		"answer": "Yes, within the specified limits"
	},
	{
		"question": "Why is compression wood NOT acceptable?",
		"options": [
			"It is very prejudicial to strength",
			"It is too strong",
			"It is susceptible to dry rot"
		],
		"answer": "It is very prejudicial to strength"
	},
	{
		"question": "When are mineral streaks acceptable?",
		"options": [
			"If the inspection fails to reveal any decay",
			"When the inspection reveals decay",
			"When the wood is wet"
		],
		"answer": "If the inspection fails to reveal any decay"
	},
	{
		"question": "Why is it necessary to examine all stains and discolouration?",
		"options": [
			"To determine if the stains are harmless, preliminary, or advanced decay",
			"To determine if the stains are caused by fuel, oil, or hydraulic fluid",
			"To determine if the stains are oil based, or latex paint"
		],
		"answer": "To determine if the stains are harmless, preliminary, or advanced decay"
	},
	{
		"question": "What types of glues are used in aircraft wood structure repair?",
		"options": [
			"Casein, Epoxies, Phenol-formaldehyde, and Resorcinol Glue",
			"School Glue, Epoxy, White Glue, and Liquid Nails",
			"Glue is not used, only nails"
		],
		"answer": "Casein, Epoxies, Phenol-formaldehyde, and Resorcinol Glue"
	},
	{
		"question": "What type of glue may have been used in OLDER AIRCRAFT construction that requires careful inspection to detect deterioration?",
		"options": ["Casein Glue", "Epoxy", "Phenol-formaldehyde"],
		"answer": "Casein Glue"
	},
	{
		"question": "What types of glue are used in MODERN AIRCRAFT wood structure repair?",
		"options": [
			"Resorcinol glue, Phenol-formaldehyde glue, and Epoxy resin glue",
			"School glue, Epoxy Resin, and Casein",
			"Resorcinol glue, Phenol-formaldehyde glue, and Casein"
		],
		"answer": "Resorcinol glue, Phenol-formaldehyde glue, and Epoxy resin glue"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the minium °F for curing wood joints with resin glue?",
		"options": [
			"70°F or as specified by the glue manufacturer",
			"0°F or as specified by the glue manufacturer",
			"100°C or as specified by the glue manufacturer"
		],
		"answer": "70°F or as specified by the glue manufacturer"
	},
	{
		"question": "Why is it important to consider the open-assembly time when gluing wooden structures?",
		"options": [
			"Because if the maximum open-assembly time is exceeded the joint may fail since the glue may begin setting up before the joint is assembled",
			"Because if the maximum open-assembly time is exceeded the glue will leach into the surrounding wood and stain the surface",
			"Because if the maximum open-assembly time isn't exceeded the joint will fail as the glue didn't have enough time to cure"
		],
		"answer": "Because if the maximum open-assembly time is exceeded the joint may fail since the glue may begin setting up before the joint is assembled"
	},
	{
		"question": "Why is it important to apply the proper clamping pressure to a glue joint?",
		"options": [
			"Clamping forces the air out, brings the wood surfaces together evenly and in part responsible for the strength of the glue line",
			"To prevent the wood from splitting",
			"To ensure the wood is not compressed"
		],
		"answer": "Clamping forces the air out, brings the wood surfaces together evenly and in part responsible for the strength of the glue line"
	},
	{
		"question": "Describe the acceptable methods used to repair elongated bolt holes found in a wooden wing spar?",
		"options": [
			"Remove the damaged section and splice in a new section or replace the entire spar",
			"Fill the holes with resin and redrill the holes",
			"Drill the hole bigger and use a bigger bolt"
		],
		"answer": "Remove the damaged section and splice in a new section or replace the entire spar"
	},
	{
		"question": "Describe the characteristics of a scarf joint.",
		"options": [
			"The pieces to be joined are tapered or bevelled to a slope of 1 to 10 or 1 to 12",
			"The pieces to be joined are tapered or bevelled to a slope of 1 to 20 or 1 to 24",
			"The pieces to be joined are tapered or bevelled to a slope of 10 to 1 or 12 to 1"
		],
		"answer": "The pieces to be joined are tapered or bevelled to a slope of 1 to 10 or 1 to 12"
	},
	{
		"question": "What are the results of insufficient gluing pressure?",
		"options": [
			"Thick glue and a weak joint",
			"Thin glue and a strong joint",
			"Thin glue and a weak joint"
		],
		"answer": "Thick glue and a weak joint"
	},
	{
		"question": "What methods are used to apply pressure to wood glue joints?",
		"options": [
			"Clamps, Brads, Nails, Elastic Straps, Weight, Vacuum Bags, Screws, and Electric and Hydraulic power presses",
			"Air Compressor",
			"Stress"
		],
		"answer": "Clamps, Brads, Nails, Elastic Straps, Weight, Vacuum Bags, Screws, and Electric and Hydraulic power presses"
	},
	{
		"question": "What type of joint is used in splicing structural members?",
		"options": ["A scarf joint", "It is never acceptable to splice structural members", "A butt joint"],
		"answer": "A scarf joint"
	},
	{
		"question": "What areas of a wood spar may NOT be spliced?",
		"options": [
			"Under a wing attachment, landing gear, engine mount, and lift strut fittings",
			"Anywhere structural",
			"Around the windows"
		],
		"answer": "Under a wing attachment, landing gear, engine mount, and lift strut fittings"
	},
	{
		"question": "What are the two primary uses for plywood in aircraft construction?",
		"options": [
			"Gusset Plates and Aircraft Skin",
			"Aircraft Skin and Windows",
			"Gusset Plates and Windows"
		],
		"answer": "Gusset Plates and Aircraft Skin"
	},
	{
		"question": "Provide examples of at least three types of aircraft skin repair.",
		"options": [
			"Scarf, Surface, Plug, and Splayed and Scarfed Patches",
			"Scarf, Plug, Sand Smooth",
			"Sand Smooth, Paper Over, Paint"
		],
		"answer": "Scarf, Surface, Plug, and Splayed and Scarfed Patches"
	},
	{
		"question": "What type of patch should be used to repair small holes in thin plywood skin if the skin is less than 1/10 inch thick?",
		"options": ["A splayed patch", "Paint over", "Paper over"],
		"answer": "A splayed patch"
	},
	{
		"question": "Why must the bevelled cut be accurate on both pieces of wood being repaired with a scarfed joint?",
		"options": [
			"The pieces must match exactly to ensure a tight glue joint",
			"The pieces must match exactly to ensure a windproof joint",
			"The pieces must match exactly to ensure a waterproof joint"
		],
		"answer": "The pieces must match exactly to ensure a tight glue joint"
	},
	{
		"question": "Name at least three different types of defects found in wood.",
		"options": [
			"Knots, Checks, Decay, Splits, Pitch Pockets, Curly Grain, Cross Grain, and Dry Rot",
			"Paint, Stain, Insects, Dry Rot, Decay, Splits, and Knots",
			"Paint, Hair, Gray, Sun Worn, Peeling Paint"
		],
		"answer": "Knots, Checks, Decay, Splits, Pitch Pockets, Curly Grain, Cross Grain, and Dry Rot"
	},
	{
		"question": "Why should the various pieces or wood be kept at room temperature for at least 24 hours prior to joining?",
		"options": [
			"To allow the moisture content to equalize, minimizing the dimensional changes in the wood",
			"To allow the moisture content to equalize, minimizing splitting",
			"To allow the temperature to equalize, minimizing the dimensional changes in the wood"
		],
		"answer": "To allow the moisture content to equalize, minimizing the dimensional changes in the wood"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the maximum number of splices that should be made in any one spar?",
		"options": ["Two", "Six", "Spars should not be spliced"],
		"answer": "Two"
	},
	{
		"question": "Always splice and reinforce plywood webs with what type of wood?"
		"options": [
			"The same type of plywood as the original",
			"Oak",
			"Spruce"
		],
		"answer": "The same type of plywood as the original"
	}
]